Tim Tang

SIPIS, SongJiang Road Suzhou, JiangSu 215000

15862410770 tang.jilong@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Experienced **End-To-End** developer, able to take on responsibility for the **analysis** and **development** of creative projects. Always strive to find **simple**, **common-sense** solutions to complex problems, adhere to **coding clean**. Currently enjoys spending most of spare time with **Ruby/Node.js/Linux**.

EXPERIENCE

Team Leader, X Plus Z Online. Inc

Suzhou, JiangSu — 2012-now

- Develop MTX-Platform coordinate with 6 engineer.
- Mentor 4 team member/codeReview/troubleShooting.
- Build project framework and coding core components.
- Do Load testing/Performance tuning/Clustering/AutoDeployment/Cl.
- Code SmartBus application server side with Node.js and iOS app.

Development Leader, Dextrys

Suzhou, JiangSu — 2010-2012

- Develop **EA Origin platform** with 30+ engineers.
- Use Spring security 3 implements authentication and authorization module.
- Based on Open Source <u>Tigase server</u>(Jabber/XMPP) customize Chat

 Server
- Based on Amazon S3 SDK implements Cloud-sync/Cloud-drive services to sync game files with S3 server.
- Based on RS4 framework develop Subscription/Catalog/Meta achievement services.
- Maintain Origin continuous integration environment with 20+ apps.

Senior Engineer, Technodex

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia — 2010-2012

- Develop PRIMS coordinate with 10 engineers.
- Implement Task Allocation module and Unit/Integration tests.
- Use JAAS implements system Single Sign On.
- Jasper reports 20+.
- Setup/Maintenance Hudson/Maven continuous integration

environment.

Engineer, YuCheng Technology

XiaMen, ShangHai — 2007-2010

- Develop RIDE/MUSE plaform coordinate with 50+ engineers.
- Implements functionalities and unit/integration cases.
- Use EXTJS to coding web page.
- Setup/Maintain CI environment with CruiseControl/ANT.

EDUCATION

Suzhou University of Science and Technology

Bachelor's Degree (Computer Science) — 2002-2006

SKILLS

- Proficiency in Spring/Hibernate/Spring Security
- Solid basis of Java/JEE
- Proficiency in Ruby/Ruby On Rails/Grails
- Proficiency in JavaScript/Node.js/Vertx.io/Shell
- Proficiency in Jasmine/EasyMock/Junit
- Excellent in Vim/iTerm2/Git/Eclipse
- Proficiency in Mysql/Postgresql/MongoDB/Redis/Oracle
- Proficiency in Mac OSX/Linux
- Excellent CET-6 fluent in spoken and written english

REFERENCES

- **Everyday** -> blog website with ROR.
- <u>Tech Talkin</u> -> personal tech blog with Jekyll.
- Everyday News -> news aggregator with ROR.
- SmartBus -> Push bus notification to iphone with Node.js and iOS6 SDK.

COMMUNITY

- GitHub: https://github.com/tim-tang
- Linkedin: http://www.linkedin.com/pub/tim-tang/45/994/238